Poop.
Virgin proclamation.
ウンコ:poop/faeces/feces, 童貞[どうてい]:virginity (esp. of a man)/male virgin|(Catholic) nun, シャウト:shout/shouting
ｳﾝｺ｡
童貞ｼｬｳﾄ｡
Kanagawa Prefectural Minegahara High School
Hot in here!
Shush!
ウフフ:giggle/chuckle/titter, きゅん:choked up (with emotion)/heart-wringing/momentary tightening of one's chest caused by powerful feelings (e.g. parting with a loved one)
(日南子)ｳﾌﾌ… きゅん きゅん｡
Term Finals
This doesn't feel like "more than schoolmates,
less than lovers" anymore.
《咲太:これは もう
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 以上[いじょう]:not less than|beyond ... (e.g. one's means)|above-mentioned||, 恋人[こいびと]:lover/sweetheart, 未満[みまん]:less than/insufficient, 雰囲気[ふんいき, ふいんき]:mood|a certain air|air
先輩以上恋人未満って
雰囲気じゃないよな｡
Will people really believe things just
fell apart over summer break?
夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday, 自然[しぜん]:nature|natural|naturally, 消滅[しょうめつ]:extinction/extinguishment|annihilation, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 信ずる[しんずる]:to believe/to believe in/to place trust in, もらえる:to be able to receive/to be able to take|could you (give me)
夏休み中に自然消滅なんて
信じてもらえるのか？》
July 10th
Episode 6: This World You Chose
よそ見[よそみ]:looking away/looking aside, 試験[しけん]:examination/exam|trial, 勉強[べんきょう]:study|diligence|discount
(麻衣)こら よそ見するな｡
試験勉強するわよ｡
Hey!
Eyes on the book.
You're studying for finals.
I'll be fine as long as I pass, you know.
赤点[あかてん]:failing mark (e.g. in exam), 回避[かいひ]:evasion/avoidance
僕は赤点さえ回避できれば
いいんだけどな｡
ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 進路[しんろ]:route/course|one's future course (e.g. after graduating high school), 考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
咲太って ちゃんと進路は
考えてるの？
Have you put any thought into your future at all?
将来[しょうらい]:future (usually near)/prospects, 麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 添い遂げる[そいとげる]:to remain married for life
将来は麻衣さんと
添い遂げたい｡
I want to be with you, till death do us part!
I'm thinking of going to college.
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
大学に行こうと考えています｡
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 進学[しんがく]:entering a higher-level school, esp. going on to university, 予定[よてい]:plans/arrangement/schedule
麻衣さんは？
進学予定｡
And you?
College as well.
仕事[しごと]:work/job|work, 専念[せんねん]:absorption/giving undivided attention/devoting oneself (to), ながら:while/during|while, 通う[かよう]:to go to and from (a place)|to go to (school, work, etc.)|to circulate (e.g. blood, electricity)|
仕事に専念するんじゃないんだ｡
しながらでも通えるでしょ｡
Not focusing on work?
I can do that and go to college.
横浜[よこはま]:Yokohama (city), 公立[こうりつ]:public (institution)
横浜にある
公立にしようと思ってる｡
I'm eyeing the public university in Yokohama.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 優秀[ゆうしゅう]:superiority/excellence
麻衣さん 優秀だしね｡
I guess you would pull that off.
You want to go to the same college as me, don't you?
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 通う[かよう]:to go to and from (a place)|to go to (school, work, etc.)|to circulate (e.g. blood, electricity)|
咲太は 私と同じ大学に
通いたいわよね？
If possible, yeah.
可能[かのう]:potential/possible/practicable, しっかり:tightly (holding on)/firmly|strongly (built), 勉強[べんきょう]:study|diligence|discount
可能なら…｡
なら しっかり勉強したいでしょ？
Then you know you need to study hard, right?
Well, yes.
煮える[にえる]:to be boiled/to be cooked, 切る[きる]:to cut|to sever (connections, ties)|to turn off (e.g. the light)||
それは まあ…｡
なによ 煮え切らないわね｡
Why are you being so wishy-washy?
The problem is my natural lack of smarts. I can't work up the motivation.
根本的[こんぽんてき]:fundamental/basic, 学力[がくりょく]:scholarly ability/scholarship/knowledge, 問題[もんだい]:question (e.g. on a test)|problem (e.g. societal, political)|question (i.e. doubt)||, いまいち:one more/another|not quite, やる気[やるき]:willingness (e.g. to do something)/eagerness/motivation
根本的な学力の問題もあるので
いまいち やる気が出ません｡
What if I said I would tutor you in the bunny-girl outfit?
バニーガール:bunny girl, 衣装[いしょう]:clothing/costume/outfit, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
じゃあ ﾊﾞﾆｰｶﾞｰﾙの衣装で
教えてあげるって言ったら？
I'd find the drive in more ways than one!
いろいろ:various|various colors (colours), やる気[やるき]:willingness (e.g. to do something)/eagerness/motivation
いろいろなやる気が出そうです！
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected
なによ？
まさか 本当に
What?
I didn't expect you to actually wear it.
着る[きる]:to wear (in modern Japanese, from the shoulders down)/to put on|to bear (guilt, etc.)
着てくれるとは
思いませんでした｡
Look at the textbook, not me.
教科書[きょうかしょ]:textbook/coursebook/schoolbook, なさる:to do, 麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
私じゃなくて教科書を見なさい｡
どうしたの？ 麻衣さん｡
What's gotten into you, Mai-san?
あんまり:remainder/rest|not very (with negative sentence), 怒る[おこる, いかる]:to get angry|to tell someone off|to be angular
なにが？
あんまり怒らないし
How do you mean?
You're being awfully accommodating. Did something happen?
なにかあった？
べつに…｡
Not really. I just figured I should
give you a carrot every once in a while.
たまに:occasionally/once in a while, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
たまには ｴｻをあげたほうが
いいと思っただけよ｡
なに？
Say what?
I'm saying I didn't think you would actually get into a fight for her!
ケンカ:quarrel/brawl/fight
あの子のためにｹﾝｶまでするとは
思わなかったってこと｡
もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance, 月曜[げつよう]:Monday
もしかして 月曜のあれ
見てた？
Wait, you saw what happened on Monday?
The closing act, yes.
途中[とちゅう]:on the way/en route|in the middle of, 靴[くつ]:shoes/boots/footwear, 洗う[あらう]:to wash|to inquire into|to purify (one's heart)|, なさる:to do
途中からね｡ あっ そうだ
靴 洗いなさいよ｡
Oh, right. Please wash your shoes.
ウンコ:poop/faeces/feces, 踏む[ふむ]:to step on|to experience|to estimate||
ｳﾝｺ踏んだっていうの
あれ ｳｿです｡
That thing about stepping on poop was a lie.
What? That's so lame!
つまる:to be packed (with)/to be full (space, schedule, etc.)|to be blocked (road, pipe, etc.), 要する[ようする]:to need/to demand/to take
なんだ つまんない｡
要するに
So, you wanted me to give you attention?
かまう:to mind/to care about|to care for, 殴る[なぐる]:to strike/to hit/to beat
かまってほしかったんですか？
殴るわよ｡
I'll punch you.
Not in the face, please.
顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face, やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
顔はやめて｡
ﾊｧ…｡
機嫌をとる[きげんをとる]:to curry favour/to butter up/to fawn over, なさる:to do
さっさと私の機嫌をとりなさいよ｡
Suck up to me already.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, なあに:what|what?
麻衣さん｡
なあに？
Mai-san.
What?
I love you.
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
好きです｡
Don't try to cheat so openly!
堂々[どうどう]:magnificent|fair|grandly|, 浮気[うわき]:extramarital sex/affair|infidelity
ｲﾃﾃ…｡
堂々と浮気するな｡
年生[ねんせい]:pupil in ... year/student in ... year, 彼氏[かれし]:boyfriend
今は あの１年生の
彼氏なんでしょ｡
You're that first-year's boyfriend right now.
How'd the exams go?
試験[しけん]:examination/exam|trial, あんまり:remainder/rest|not very (with negative sentence)
試験できたか？
(朋絵)あっ あんまり｡
Not very well. You?
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
先輩は？
ﾊﾞｯﾁﾘ｡
Perfectly.
Perfectly?!
できたの!?
できなかった｡
Perfectly wrong.
Ah, so you're one of us.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, じゃん:isn't it
なんだ 先輩 仲間じゃん｡
I've made a plan to hit the beach with Rena-chan and the girls.
海[うみ, み]:sea/ocean/waters, 約束[やくそく]:promise|convention|destiny
玲奈ちゃんたちと
海に行く約束してるの｡
学校[がっこう]:school, 水着[みずぎ]:bathing suit/swimsuit/swimmers, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
私 学校の水着しか
持ってなくて｡
But I only have my school swimsuit.
中学[ちゅうがく]:middle school/junior high school, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
中学ので いいんじゃないか？
なんで 戻るの｡
Won't your middle school swimsuit do?
Why would I go back to that?
あっ これとか どうかな？
Oh, how about this?
Just so you know, I'm not into padding.
大量[たいりょう]:large quantity/massive (quantity)/mass (e.g. mass production, mass transit, mass destruction), 詰め物[つめもの]:filling or packing material/stuffing/padding, 喜ぶ[よろこぶ]:to be delighted|to congratulate|to gratefully accept, 趣味[しゅみ]:hobby/pastime|tastes
僕は 大量の詰め物を見て
喜ぶ趣味はないな｡
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 見せる[みせる]:to show/to display, 水着[みずぎ]:bathing suit/swimsuit/swimmers
先輩に見せるためじゃないし｡
そういう水着はさぁ
I won't be wearing this for you, anyway.
Save those swimsuits for when you've grown that much.
くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that, 成長[せいちょう]:growth/grow to adulthood, からにする:to empty/to vacate/to evacuate
あのくらいに成長してからにしろ｡
一生[いっしょう]:whole life/a lifetime|(the only, the greatest, etc.) of one's life, 無理[むり]:unreasonable|impossible|forcible||
そんなの一生無理！
That's never happening!
失礼[しつれい, しつらい]:discourtesy|Excuse me|to leave|, ばっか:only/merely|approximately
ってゆうか そういう
失礼なことばっか言ってると
Y'know, if you make a habit of saying this stuff,
Sakurajima-senpai will end up hating you.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 嫌う[きらう]:to hate/to dislike/to loathe, 確実[かくじつ]:certainty/reliability/soundness, 殴る[なぐる]:to strike/to hit/to beat
桜島先輩に嫌われるよ｡
言ったら確実に殴られるな｡
If I said it to her, she'd definitely punch me.
うれしい:happy/glad/pleasant
なんかうれしそう…｡
Why are you smiling about that?
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 海[うみ, み]:sea/ocean/waters
桜島先輩とは
海行ったりするの？
Will you go to the beach with her and stuff?
Dunno.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 芸能人[げいのうじん]:performer/entertainer/celebrity, 無理[むり]:unreasonable|impossible|forcible||
どうかな 麻衣さんは芸能人だから
そういうのは無理かもな｡
She's famous, so it might not be possible.
You can count on me, okay?
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 協力[きょうりょく]:cooperation/collaboration, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair), うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious
私 先輩に協力してあげるね｡
桜島先輩と うまくいくように｡
I'll help you get together
with Sakurajima-senpai.
And whose fault is it that we're not together right now, huh?
つきあい:association/socializing/socialising, 遠のく[とおのく]:to become distant/to recede
誰のせいで おつきあいが
遠のいたと思ってんだよ｡
応援[おうえん]:aid/assistance/help
うっ… だから応援するんだよ｡
はいはい｡
Th-That's why I'm gonna help!
Yeah, yeah. I appreciate the sentiment, at least.
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
気持ちだけもらっておくよ｡
なあ 古賀｡
なに？
Hey, Koga.
What?
別れる[わかれる]:to part (usu. of people)|to separate (of a couple)|to lose (e.g. one's mother), 方[かた]:direction|person|method of||, 方[ほう]:direction|side (of an argument, etc.)|type||, 考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
別れ方 考えておいたほうが
よくないか？
We should figure out the way we'll break up.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 方[かた]:direction|person|method of||, 方[ほう]:direction|side (of an argument, etc.)|type||
うん わかってる｡
先輩のふり方なら
Yeah, I know.
I've already thought of a way to dump you, so don't worry.
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||, 安心[あんしん]:relief/peace of mind, 安心[あんじん]:obtaining peace of mind through faith or ascetic practice
考えてあるから 安心して｡
待て 僕がふられるのか？
Wait, I'm the one getting dumped?
結局[けっきょく]:after all|conclusion|ending of a game of Go, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 未練[みれん]:lingering affection/attachment/regret, たらたら:drop-by-drop/dripping|incessantly (esp. speaking, e.g. complaints, compliments)
結局 先輩は
桜島先輩に未練たらたらで
Even after everything,
you still can't get over Sakurajima-senpai.
気づく[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise, 設定[せってい]:establishment/creation|options setting
それに気づいた私に
ふられる設定｡
I realize that and break up with you.
That's awfully realistic.
微妙[びみょう]:delicate|difficult|doubtful, 微妙[みみょう]:unspeakably wonderful/sublime/exquisite, リアル:real/realistic/true to life, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
微妙にﾘｱﾙだな｡
先輩なんて知らない！ って
In the end, I say, "Screw you!"
and slap you in the face.
最後[さいご]:last|no sooner than|one's final moments, ひっぱたく:to slap/to strike/to spank, ことにする:to make a distinction/to differ/to be different, ことにする:to decide to|to pretend that
最後は ひっぱたいたことにする｡
You're not actually gonna do it, right?
実演[じつえん]:demonstration/presentation|stage show, リアリティ:reality, 大事[だいじ, おおごと]:important/valuable|safe (Tochigi dialect)
それ 実演はしないよな？
ﾘｱﾘﾃｨは大事｡
Realism is important.
終業式[しゅうぎょうしき]:closing ceremony, 空ける[あける]:to open (a door, etc.)|to open (for business, etc.)|to empty||, 空ける[うつける]:to become empty (hollow)|to relax from a tense situation into a vacant or absent minded state
やるのか…｡
終業式のあとは空けておいてね｡
So you are?
Keep yourself free after the closing ceremony.
海[うみ, み]:sea/ocean/waters, デート:date/go on a date, 帰り[かえり]:return/coming back, ケンカ:quarrel/brawl/fight, たって:strongly hoping or requesting (of something that is difficult to be brought to fruition), たって:even if/even though|however, 想定[そうてい]:hypothesis/supposition/assumption
海ﾃﾞｰﾄの帰りにｹﾝｶしたって
想定だから｡
The plan is for us to fight on the way
back from a beach date.
July 18th
Rise and shine, Onii-chan!
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, 朝[あさ, あした]:morning, 朝[ちょう]:dynasty|reign|period||
(かえで)お兄ちゃん 朝ですよ｡
おはよう:good morning, かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.)
ん… おはよう かえで｡
Morning, Kaede.
Good morning!
おはようございます:good morning
(かえで)おはようございます｡
テレビ:television/TV, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]今日は７月18日…｡
(かえで)明日から夏休みですね｡
Today is July 18th.
Summer break starts tomorrow, huh?
夏[なつ]:summer, 夏[か]:Xia (dynasty of China; perhaps mythological), スイカ:watermelon (Citrullus lanatus), スイカ:Suica (rechargeable prepaid IC card that can be used as a train pass in the greater Tokyo, Osaka and Sendai regions and also as electric money in some stores)
夏といえば 何だろうな｡
ｽｲｶです｡
What comes to mind first when you think summer?
Watermelon!
I guess I'll buy one sometime.
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, 買う[かう]:to buy|to value|to stir, 丸い[まるい, まろい]:round/circular|harmonious
じゃあ 今度 買ってくるか｡
丸いのがいいです｡
I want a round one.
What're your plans for summer, Sakuta?
夏[なつ]:summer, 夏[か]:Xia (dynasty of China; perhaps mythological), 予定[よてい]:plans/arrangement/schedule, バイト:work (esp. part time or casual)
(国見)咲太 夏の予定は？
ﾊﾞｲﾄ｡
Work.
古賀さんもいるしな｡
And there's Koga-san, too.
You?
バイト:work (esp. part time or casual), 部活[ぶかつ]:club activities, デート:date/go on a date
国見は？
ﾊﾞｲﾄ 部活 ﾃﾞｰﾄ｡
Work, basketball, dates.
Living the life, huh?
青春[せいしゅん]:youth/springtime of life/adolescent, 長者[ちょうじゃ, ちょうしゃ]:millionaire|one's superior|virtuous and gentle person||, 言える[いえる]:to be possible to say/to be able to say
青春長者め｡
(国見)人のこと言えないだろ｡
You're one to talk.
The long summer break begins tomorrow.
いよいよ:more and more/all the more|at last, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday, 始まる[はじまる]:to begin|to happen (again)|to date (from)
え～ いよいよ 明日から
長い夏休みが始まります｡
皆[みんな, みな]:all/everyone|everything, 願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
そこで 皆さんに ２つのことを
お願いします｡
I want you all to keep two things in mind...
It's time for the final date.
いよいよ:more and more/all the more|at last, 最後[さいご]:last|no sooner than|one's final moments, デート:date/go on a date
《いよいよ最後のﾃﾞｰﾄ｡
全校[ぜんこう]:the whole school, 生徒[せいと]:pupil, 終わり[おわり]:the end
僕たちが全校生徒についたｳｿも
今日で終わりだ》
The lie we told the whole school ends today.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|
あっ 先輩のほうが早かった｡
Oh, you got here first?
I changed into my swimsuit
in the locker room at school.
水着[みずぎ]:bathing suit/swimsuit/swimmers, 学校[がっこう]:school, 更衣室[こういしつ]:locker room/changing room/dressing room, 着る[きる]:to wear (in modern Japanese, from the shoulders down)/to put on|to bear (guilt, etc.)
水着 学校の更衣室で着てきたの｡
You've got this dirty look in your eyes.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, エロい:erotic/pornographic|eminent
先輩 目がｴﾛい｡
知ってる｡
I know.
I'm telling you not to stare!
あんまり:remainder/rest|not very (with negative sentence), 意味[いみ]:meaning/significance
あんまり見ないでって意味！
泳ぐ[およぐ]:to swim
よし 泳ぐか｡
Okay, time to swim.
Huh? No thoughts?
感想[かんそう]:impressions/thoughts, あんまり:remainder/rest|not very (with negative sentence)
えっ 感想なし？
あんまり見てほしくないんだろ？
You don't want me to stare, right?
まっ かわいいと思うぞ｡
か かわいいって言うな！
But well, you look very cute.
D-Don't call me cute!
じゃあ 何て言ってほしいんだ？
What do you want me to say, then?
情緒[じょうちょ, じょうしょ]:emotion/feeling|atmosphere, 不安定[ふあんてい]:instability/insecurity/crankiness
か かわいい… かな｡
古賀は情緒不安定なのか？
That I'm c-cute, I guess?
Wow, you're all over the place.
That's just how a girl's heart works!
乙女心[おとめごころ]:girl's feeling/maiden's mind
乙女心は そういうものなの！
いっちょんわからん｡
I hadn't an inklin'.
You really know how to get on someone's nerves.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, ホント:truth/reality/actuality, ムカつく:to feel irritated/to feel offended|to feel sick
先輩 ﾎﾝﾄ ﾑｶつく｡
ﾑｶつかれたから
Well, since you're so annoyed at me,
I might as well get some grilled corn.
焼く[やく]:to burn|to roast|to heat||, トウモロコシ:corn (Zea mays)/maize, 食べる[たべる]:to eat|to live on (e.g. a salary)/to live off
僕は焼きﾄｳﾓﾛｺｼでも食べるかな｡
私も行く！
Me too!
それ！
Take that!
どっち:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives), 城[しろ]:castle, 城[じょう]:castle (in place names), 波[なみ]:wave, 波[ぽ]:Poland, 打ち勝つ[うちかつ]:to conquer (e.g. an enemy)|to overcome (a difficulty)|to out-hit, 勝負[しょうぶ]:victory or defeat/match/contest
どっちの城が波に打ち勝つか
勝負な｡
Let's see whose castle can survive the waves.
負ける[まける]:to lose|to succumb|to be inferior to||, カキ氷[かきごおり, カキごおり]:shaved ice (usually served with flavored simple syrup)/Italian ice/Sno-cone, おごり:luxury/extravagance|treat (i.e. at somebody's expense), おごり:arrogance/haughtiness/conceitedness
負けたほうがｶｷ氷おごりね｡
Whoever loses pays for the shaved ice.
Saved by the butt, huh?
尻[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|, 尻[しり]:buttocks|undersurface|last place|, 救う[すくう]:to rescue from/to help out of/to save, うるさい:noisy/loud|annoying
尻に救われたな｡
うるさいな！
Oh, shut up!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 腹[はら]:abdomen|womb|one's mind||, 減る[へる]:to decrease (in size or number)/to diminish/to abate
ねぇ 先輩｡
また腹減ったのか？
Hey, Senpai.
Hungry again?
ありがと:Thank you
今日まで ありがと｡
Thanks for everything.
Here.
はい｡
握手[あくしゅ]:handshake
握手だよ｡
なんで？
Let's shake hands.
Why?
Breakup handshake.
別れ[わかれ]:parting/separation/farewell
お別れの｡
In the end, you were still in love with Sakurajima-senpai.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 結局[けっきょく]:after all|conclusion|ending of a game of Go, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
先輩は結局
桜島先輩のことが好きで
I got fed up with that and dumped you.
愛想を尽かす[あいそをつかす]:to be disgusted with/to run out of patience/to fall out of love
私に愛想を尽かされ
ふられました｡
ﾋﾞﾝﾀはしなくていいのか？
Aren't you gonna slap me?
I'll just say I did.
ことにする:to make a distinction/to differ/to be different, ことにする:to decide to|to pretend that
それは したことにしておく｡
ひっぱたく:to slap/to strike/to spank, 超[ちょう, チョー]:super-/ultra-|over (after a number or counter), 恩[おん]:favour/favor/obligation
ここで ひっぱたいたら
私 超恩知らずだし｡
I mean, if I slapped you now,
I'd be a total ingrate.
そっか まあ なら…｡
I see. Well, then.
疲れ[つかれ]:tiredness/fatigue
お疲れ｡
うん｡
Cheers.
Yeah.
Have a nice summer break.
夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
いい夏休みをな｡
先輩も
You too.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, つきあえる:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあえる:to poke each other/to jab each other
桜島先輩と つきあえるといいね｡
I hope Sakurajima-senpai says yes.
気長[きなが]:patient/leisurely
まっ 気長にやるよ｡
Well, I'll try my best.
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, 朝[あさ, あした]:morning, 朝[ちょう]:dynasty|reign|period||
お兄ちゃん 朝ですよ｡
Rise and shine, Onii-chan!
かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.)
ん？ あのな かえで｡
はい｡
Look, Kaede.
Yes?
世の中[よのなか]:society/the world/the times, 夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday
世の中には 夏休みというものが
あるんだぞ｡
There exists this thing called summer break.
But doesn't it only start tomorrow?
夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future
でも 夏休みは明日からですよね？
いや 今日だろ｡
Nah, today.
明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future
いえ 明日です｡
No, it starts tomorrow.
Onii-chan?
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister
お兄ちゃん？
Kaede, do you wanna eat watermelon?
かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.), スイカ:watermelon (Citrullus lanatus), スイカ:Suica (rechargeable prepaid IC card that can be used as a train pass in the greater Tokyo, Osaka and Sendai regions and also as electric money in some stores), 食べる[たべる]:to eat|to live on (e.g. a salary)/to live off
かえで ｽｲｶ食べたいか？
えっ 食べたいです｡
Huh? I do.
July 18th (Round 2)
丸い[まるい, まろい]:round/circular|harmonious, 今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, 買う[かう]:to buy|to value|to stir
丸いのを今度買ってくるよ｡
I'll buy a round one sometime.
Huh...
アプリ:app/application
え～ あっ このｱﾌﾟﾘ？
Oh, you mean this app?
Lemme see.
Yeah, that's the one.
(亜矢)どれどれ？
(玲奈)朋絵｡
Tomoe.
急[きゅう]:urgent|sharp|rapid||, 教室[きょうしつ]:classroom|department|single-room school, 困る[こまる]:to be troubled/to be worried/to be bothered
急に教室に来られると困る｡
Don't just turn up at my classroom.
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 仕方ない[しかたない]:it can't be helped/it's inevitable/it's no use
悪いとは思ったが仕方ないだろ｡
I did feel bad about that,
but what else could I do?
Did something bad happen?
まずい:poor-quality/shoddy|unskillful, まずい:unappetising/unappetizing|unskillful
何かまずいことあったのか？
なんで？
Why?
What do you mean, why?
We looped back again.
ループ:loop/ring network
なんでって… またﾙｰﾌﾟしただろ？
え？
Huh?
回[かい]:counter for occurrences|a time|inning (baseball)||, ううん:no|er, well, ...
今日 ２回目だよな？
ううん｡
Today's the second time, right?
Nah.
Wait a second.
回[かい]:counter for occurrences|a time|inning (baseball)||
ちょっと待て 古賀は
１回目なのか？
It's your first time?
Yeah.
Got it. Forget what I just said.
いったん:once|for a short time/briefly, いったん:one end/an end|part, 忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of
わかった いったん
今のは忘れてくれ｡
放課後[ほうかご]:after school, 予定[よてい]:plans/arrangement/schedule, 通り[とおり]:avenue|coming and going|flow (of water, air, etc.)||, 通り[どおり]:in accordance with|roughly|Street
放課後は？
予定通りでいい あとでな｡
What about after school?
We can stick to the plan.
Later.
どう思う？
What do you think?
Did you hit your head, Azusagawa?
頭[とう]:counter for large animals (e.g. head of cattle), 頭[あたま, かしら]:head|hair (on one's head)|mind||
(理央)梓川 頭は大丈夫？
どういう:somehow/how/in what way, 意味[いみ]:meaning/significance
どういう意味だ？
What's that supposed to mean?
You're asking me something
even a little kid would know.
小学生[しょうがくせい]:elementary school student/primary school student/grade school student, 質問をする[しつもんをする]:to ask a question/to ask questions
小学生でもわかるような
質問をしてきたから｡
If you're right and that first-year...
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||, とおり:avenue/street|coming and going, とおり:penetration (as of light), 年生[ねんせい]:pupil in ... year/student in ... year
梓川が考えたとおり
その１年生…｡
悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra
古賀朋絵な｡
その子がﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔なら
Koga Tomoe.
If she's Laplace's demon, the answer is simple.
答え[こたえ, いらえ]:answer/reply/response, 簡単[かんたん]:simple/easy|brief
答えは簡単でしょ｡
簡単か？
Is it?
７月18日と19日に
There must be a crucial difference
between July 18th and 19th.
決定的[けっていてき]:definite/final/decisive, 違い[ちがい]:difference/discrepancy
何か決定的な違いが
あるんじゃないの？
For example, a change in the
relationship between you two.
例えば[たとえば]:for example/for instance/e.g., 関係性[かんけいせい]:relationship/relation, 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
例えば 梓川との関係性が
変わってしまうとか｡
気づく[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise
本当は 梓川も
気づいてるんじゃないの？
Deep down, surely you've realized it too.
Realized what?
再び[ふたたび]:again/once more/a second time, サイコロ:dice/die, 振り出す[ふりだす]:to shake out|to draw a check (bill, draft, etc.)|to infuse (e.g. in hot water), 理由[りゆう, わけ]:reason/pretext/motive
何にだよ｡
彼女が再びｻｲｺﾛを振り出した理由｡
The reason she started rerolling again.
今回[こんかい]:now/this time/lately, 関する[かんする]:to concern/to be related
ただ 今回に関して言えば
But this time, Koga's not aware of the loop.
回[かい]:counter for occurrences|a time|inning (baseball)||, 気づく[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise
古賀は 今日が２回目だって
気づいてないんだよ｡
悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra
だとしたら梓川が悪魔なのかもね｡
僕は違う｡
In that case, maybe you're the demon.
I'm not.
やっぱり:too/also|still, 可能性[かのうせい]:potentiality/likelihood/possibility
なら やっぱり 可能性は
１つしかない｡
Then that leaves only one possibility.
１つか…｡
そう｡
Only one, huh?
Right.
She's lying.
ウソをつく:to tell a lie/to fib
彼女はｳｿをついている｡
Teenage Pig Doesn't
Dream of Bunny Girls
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|
あっ 先輩のほうが早かった｡
Oh, you got here first?
水着[みずぎ]:bathing suit/swimsuit/swimmers, 学校[がっこう]:school, 更衣室[こういしつ]:locker room/changing room/dressing room, 着る[きる]:to wear (in modern Japanese, from the shoulders down)/to put on|to bear (guilt, etc.)
水着 学校の更衣室で着てきたの｡
I changed into my swimsuit
in the locker room at school.
You've got this dirty look in your eyes.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, エロい:erotic/pornographic|eminent
先輩 目がｴﾛい｡
Take that!
それ！
(はしゃぎ声)
ありがと:Thank you
今日まで ありがと｡
Thanks for everything.
July 18th
(Round 3)
泳ぐ[およぐ]:to swim
よし 泳ぐか｡
Okay, time to swim.
感想[かんそう]:impressions/thoughts
えっ 感想なし？
Huh? No thoughts?
Thanks for everything.
ありがと:Thank you
今日まで ありがと｡
Rise and shine, Onii-chan!
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, 朝[あさ, あした]:morning, 朝[ちょう]:dynasty|reign|period||
お兄ちゃん 朝ですよ｡
July 18th
(Round 4)
なあ 国見｡
ん？
Hey, Kunimi.
ありがたい:grateful/thankful/welcome
彼女いるよな？
ありがたいことにな｡
You have a girlfriend, right?
Luckily.
思いを寄せる[おもいをよせる]:to give one's heart to/to fall in love|to turn one's mind towards, 他[ほか]:other (place, thing, person)|outside|nothing except|, 他[た]:other (esp. people and abstract matters), 女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl
そんなお前に 思いを寄せている
他の女子がいたら どうする？
What if there were another girl
who was also in love with you?
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, 気づく[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise
その子の気持ちに気づいたら
国見は どうするんだ？
What would you do if you
became aware of her feelings?
例えば[たとえば]:for example/for instance/e.g., 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
それ 誰のこと言ってるんだよ｡
例えばの話｡
Who are you talking about?
I'm just speaking hypothetically.
例えば[たとえば]:for example/for instance/e.g., 気づく[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise, バレる:to leak out (a secret)/to be exposed (a lie, improper behaviour, etc.) (behavior)
例えばねぇ… 俺が気づいてること
ﾊﾞﾚてんのかな｡
Hypothetically, huh?
Does she know that I know?
She hasn't realized yet.
気づく[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise
今は まだ気づいてない｡
今はねぇ｡
"Yet," huh?
本人[ほんにん]:the person himself, 胸[むね, むな]:chest|breasts|heart||, 秘める[ひめる]:to hide/to keep to oneself, 思い[おもい]:thought|imagination|desire||
(国見)本人が胸に秘めた思いを
Honestly, it wouldn't feel right to drag out
the feelings she was keeping hidden.
無理やり[むりやり]:forcibly/against one's will, 引っ張る[ひっぱる]:to pull|to string (lines)|to pull towards oneself (e.g. someone's sleeve)||
無理やり
引っ張り出させるっていうのは
正直[しょうじき]:honesty/integrity|honestly, 抵抗[ていこう]:resistance|reluctance|resistance||
正直 抵抗あるよな｡
自意識[じいしき]:self-consciousness, 過剰[かじょう]:excess/surplus/over-, 気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of, 様[ざま]:mess|-ways|in the act of ...|, 様[さま]:Mr.|makes words more polite (usu. in fixed expressions)|state
自意識過剰って気もするし
俺って何様だよって｡
It'd also be kinda egotistical.
Like, who the hell do I think I am?
けど このままでいいとも
思ってない｡
But I'd also know that this couldn't go on.
正解[せいかい]:correct/right/correct interpretation (answer, solution)
どうするのが正解なんだ？
聞いたのは僕だ｡
What'd be the right thing to do?
I'm the one asking.
いよいよ:more and more/all the more|at last, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday, 始まる[はじまる]:to begin|to happen (again)|to date (from)
え～ いよいよ 明日から
長い夏休みが始まります｡
The long summer break begins tomorrow.
皆[みんな, みな]:all/everyone|everything, 願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
そこで 皆さんに ２つのことを
お願いします｡
I want you all to keep two things in mind...
Koga is lying.
ウソをつく:to tell a lie/to fib
《古賀はｳｿをついている》
Senpai? The beach is this way.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 海[うみ, み]:sea/ocean/waters
先輩？ 海 こっちだよ｡
度目[どめ]:the Nth time
僕は 今日が４度目なんだよ｡
Today's my fourth time.
You mean you're bored of the beach?
海[うみ, み]:sea/ocean/waters, 飽きる[あきる]:to get tired of/to lose interest in/to have enough, 空気[くうき]:air|mood|someone with no presence, 読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess, 助かる[たすかる]:to be saved|to escape harm|to be helped
海は飽きたってこと？
古賀は空気が読めて助かる｡
I'm glad you're so quick on the uptake.
最初[さいしょ]:beginning/outset/first, デート:date/go on a date, そびれる:to miss a chance/to fail to do
江の島に行くの？
最初のﾃﾞｰﾄで行きそびれただろ｡
We're going to Enoshima?
We didn't get to on our first date, remember?
足[あし]:foot|leg|gait||, 足[そく]:counter for pairs (of socks, shoes, etc.), パンパン:kapow/bang/slap
(２人)ﾊｧ…｡
足ﾊﾟﾝﾊﾟﾝ｡
Gah! My legs are dead!
Suck it up, first-year.
年生[ねんせい]:pupil in ... year/student in ... year, 理屈[りくつ]:theory/reason
１年生のくせに｡
なに その理屈｡
What does that have to do with anything?
Hetsunomiya
Main Shrine
縁[ゆかり]:related to (some person or place)/affinity/connection, 縁[えん, えにし]:fate|relationship (e.g. between two people)|family ties||, むすび:ending/conclusion|join, 絵馬[えま, えうま]:votive picture (originally of horse)
縁むすびの絵馬だってさ｡
Look, wish tablets for matchmaking.
書く[かく]:to write/to compose|to draw, 様[ざま]:mess|-ways|in the act of ...|, 様[さま]:Mr.|makes words more polite (usu. in fixed expressions)|state
書いていくか｡
えっ 神様にｳｿつくの？
Wanna fill out one?
Huh? You wanna lie to the gods?
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 罰当たり[ばちあたり]:damned/cursed/accursed
せ 先輩 罰当たりだって｡
S-Senpai...
That's blasphemy!
騙す[だます]:to trick/to cheat|to coax, 決める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||, 時点[じてん]:point in time/occasion
みんなを騙すって決めた時点で
The moment we decided to fool everyone,
we already punched our tickets to Hell.
地獄[じごく]:hell, 落ちる[おちる]:to fall down|to be omitted|to decrease||, 覚悟[かくご]:resolution/resignation/readiness
地獄に落ちる覚悟は
できてんだろ｡
Sakuta
ほら｡
あ…｡
Here.
私はいいけど…｡
Not that I mind.
Azusagawa Sakuta
Koga Tomoe
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
あっ あ～ ちょっと先輩？
Wait, Senpai!
Koga Tomoe
Azusagawa Sakuta
お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please, 混ぜる[まぜる]:to mix/to stir/to blend, 罰が当たる[ばちがあたる]:to incur divine punishment/to pay for one's sins|You'll pay for that!
みんなの本当のお願いの中に
ｳｿを混ぜたら 罰が当たるって｡
We can't mix in a lie among real wishes!
The gods will punish us!
Let me just take it home.
持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||, 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
私 持って帰るから｡
I'm the only one lying, so it'll be fine.
ウソをつく:to tell a lie/to fib, 平気[へいき]:coolness/calmness|all right
ｳｿをついてるのは
僕だけだから 平気だろ｡
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
先輩…｡
Senpai.
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill
ん？
さっきの… なんでもない｡
What you said earlier...
Never mind.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 海[うみ, み]:sea/ocean/waters
ねぇ 先輩 今からでも
海行かない？
Hey, Senpai. It's not too late to hit the beach.
水着[みずぎ]:bathing suit/swimsuit/swimmers
私 この下 水着だし｡
I'm wearing my swimsuit underneath and all.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 終わり[おわり]:the end
先輩？
古賀 もうｳｿは終わりだ｡
Senpai?
Koga, enough with the lies.
えっ あ うん
今日までだしね｡
Huh? Oh yeah, it ends today.
That's not what I mean.
そうじゃない｡
You've got this scary look, y'know?
顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face, 怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
顔 なんか怖いよ｡
なに？ どうしたの？
What's wrong?
気づく[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise
僕が気づかないと思ったか？
Did you really think I wouldn't catch on?
Seriously, what are you talking about?
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
だから 何の話？
Even if it was all pretense,
I've been your boyfriend for three weeks.
約[やく]:approximately|promise|shortening|, 週間[しゅうかん]:weeks (period of), 恋人[こいびと]:lover/sweetheart
ｳｿでも 約３週間
恋人やってたんだぞ｡
空気[くうき]:air|mood|someone with no presence, 読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess, 読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess
僕は空気が読めているくせに
読まないんだ｡
It's not that I can't take a hint. I just don't.
If you won't say it, I will.
古賀が言わなくても 僕は言う｡
何度[なんど]:how many times?/how often?, サイコロ:dice/die, 振る[ふる]:to wave|to sprinkle|to cast (actor)||, 振る[ぶる]:assuming the air of .../behaving like ...|to put on airs, 直す[なおす]:to cure|to fix|to do over again (after -masu base of verb)||, 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different
古賀が 何度ｻｲｺﾛを振り直しても
人の気持ちは変わらない｡
You can roll the dice as many times as you want,
but people's feelings don't change so easily.
ｳｿは本当にならないし
本当はｳｿにならないんだ｡
A lie won't become the truth,
and the truth won't become a lie.
Even after a hundred times?
回[かい]:counter for occurrences|a time|inning (baseball)||
100回やっても？
ああ｡
Yeah.
回[かい]:counter for occurrences|a time|inning (baseball)||
1,000回やっても？
そうだ｡
Even after a thousand times?
That's right.
万[ばん]:many/all, 万[まん, よろず]:10,000|myriad|everything|, 回[かい]:counter for occurrences|a time|inning (baseball)||, 億[おく]:10^8/100,000,000/hundred million, 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different
１万回でも？
１億回やっても変わらない｡
And ten thousand?
Even a billion times won't change anything.
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), 麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
僕が好きなのは麻衣さんだ｡
Mai-san is the one I love.
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 繰り返す[くりかえす]:to repeat/to do something over again
同じことを繰り返しても
If you keep repeating the same day,
your feelings won't get any closure either.
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.)
古賀の気持ちだって
ずっとそのままだ｡
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, ウソつき:liar (sometimes said with not much seriousness)/fibber
先輩 ｳｿつきだよ｡
You're a liar, Senpai.
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different
気持ちは変わるよ｡
People's feelings do change.
繰り返す[くりかえす]:to repeat/to do something over again, 積み重なる[つみかさなる]:to accumulate
繰り返した分だけ
積み重なっていく…｡
They can grow stronger with each loop.
積み重なる[つみかさなる]:to accumulate
積み重なっていった…｡
They did for me.
忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of, 決める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||
忘れようって決めて
なのに 忘れられなくて
I decided to forget about them, but I couldn't.
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, 忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of
今度こそ忘れようと思ったのに
ﾀﾞﾒだった｡
Each time I thought this would be the last, it wasn't.
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, さよなら:good-bye, 決める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||
この気持ちと
さよならしようって決めたのに｡
Even though I'd decided to say goodbye to these feelings.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun, 最後[さいご]:last|no sooner than|one's final moments, デート:date/go on a date
今日はね 先輩と楽しく
最後のﾃﾞｰﾄをして
Today, I have to have a fun last date with you
恋人[こいびと]:lover/sweetheart, 笑顔[えがお]:smiling face/smile, 終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close, いける:to arrange (flowers)/to plant|living, いける:to be good (at)/to go well|to look (taste, etc.) good
ｳｿの恋人を 笑顔で
終わらせなきゃいけないの｡
and end this pretend-lovers thing with a smile.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious
そして 先輩は
桜島先輩と うまくいって
Later, you'll get together with Sakurajima-senpai,
学期[がっき]:school term/semester
２学期になったら
私は よかったねって
and when second term rolls around,
I'll tease you by going all, "Good for you."
少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, 意地[いじ]:stubbornness|disposition|appetite, 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, からかう:to ridicule/to tease/to mock
少し意地悪く
先輩をからかうんだよ｡
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 友達[ともだち]:friend/companion
それで 先輩と友達になるの｡
And then, I'll become friends with you.
仲よく[なかよく]:on good terms with/on cordial terms with|to make friends with, 話せる[はなせる]:to be able to speak/to be able to talk|to be understanding, 甘える[あまえる]:to behave like a spoiled child/to fawn on|to take advantage of, 年上[としうえ]:older/senior, 友達[ともだち]:friend/companion
仲よく何でも話せて
ちょっと甘えられる 年上の友達｡
You'll be an older friend who I can speak
my mind with, and who'll baby me a little.
今まで[いままで]:until now/so far/up to the present
今までのことも
We'll look back at these three weeks and go,
"Being pretend lovers was pretty fun!"
恋人[こいびと]:lover/sweetheart, ごっこ:playing at (something)/game of make-believe/something done together, 結構[けっこう]:splendid|sufficient|well enough||, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
ｳｿの恋人ごっこ
結構楽しかったねって
思い出[おもいで]:memories/recollections/reminiscence, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.)
思い出話にして
これからも ずっと
And we'll be good friends forever.
仲よく[なかよく]:on good terms with/on cordial terms with|to make friends with
仲よくするんだから｡
するんだから…｡
We have to be.
望む[のぞむ]:to desire|to wish for|to see
私が望んでいるのは それだけ｡
That's all I want.
特別[とくべつ]:special, 欲しい[ほしい]:wanted/wished for|I want (you) to
特別な何かを
欲しがっているわけじゃない｡
I'm not asking for anything special.
わがまま:selfishness/egoism|disobedience
わがままだって言ってない｡
I'm not being selfish.
I'm not hurting anyone either.
迷惑[めいわく, べいこく]:trouble/bother/annoyance, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
誰にも迷惑だってかけてないよ｡
なのに… なのに…｡
So...
So why...
Why won't tomorrow come?!
明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future
どうして
明日になってくれないの！
朝[あさ, あした]:morning, 朝[ちょう]:dynasty|reign|period||, 起きる[おきる]:to get up|to wake up|to occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents), 昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday, 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, 大きい[おおきい]:big/large/great
なんで朝起きると 昨日よりも
気持ちが大きくなってるの!?
Why are my feelings growing stronger each morning?!
ひどい:cruel/heartless|violent
こんなのひどいよ…｡
Why is this happening when I'd decided to pretend they never existed?
ことにする:to make a distinction/to differ/to be different, ことにする:to decide to|to pretend that, 決める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||
なかったことにするって
決めたのに…｡
そんなことしなくていい｡
No need to do that.
I have to!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), じゃん:isn't it
しなきゃﾀﾞﾒ！ だって先輩は
桜島先輩のことが好きじゃん｡
I mean, you love Sakurajima-senpai!
なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 迷惑[めいわく, べいこく]:trouble/bother/annoyance
私なんか迷惑でしょ？
You just find me a bother, right?
Friends don't have these kinds of emotions.
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, 友達[ともだち]:friend/companion, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
こんな気持ち
友達は持ってないもん｡
Nobody feels this way about a friend!
友達[ともだち]:friend/companion, 感情[かんじょう]:emotion/feeling/feelings
友達にはない感情だもん！
When did I ever say you were a bother?
迷惑[めいわく, べいこく]:trouble/bother/annoyance
僕が いつ迷惑だって言った｡
ひどい:cruel/heartless|violent
ひどいよ…｡
You're mean.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 嫌い[きらい]:dislike|suspicion|distinction, 嫌い[ぎらい]:dislike/hatred/fear, 大嫌い[だいきらい]:detestable/abhorrent/loathsome
先輩なんて嫌い 大嫌い！
I hate you! I hate you so much!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, いける:to arrange (flowers)/to plant|living, いける:to be good (at)/to go well|to look (taste, etc.) good, じゃん:isn't it, いっぱい:one defeat, いっぱい:amount necessary to fill a container (e.g. cupful, spoonful, etc.)/drink (usu. alcoholic)|full, 優しい[やさしい]:tender/kind/gentle
先輩がいけないんじゃん
私にいっぱい優しくしたから！
This is all your fault for being so nice to me!
気を遣う[きをつかう]:to pay attention to another's needs/to attend to/to fuss about, 必要[ひつよう]:necessary/needed|necessity, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
そうだよ だから 僕に
気を遣う必要なんてないんだ｡
That's right. So you don't need to hold back on my behalf.
大嫌い[だいきらい]:detestable/abhorrent/loathsome
こんな私も大嫌い｡
こんなの私じゃない！
I hate myself too! This isn't who I am!
いいや 古賀だよ それも古賀だ｡
No, it is. It's a part of you.
You're wrong! This isn't me!
違う これは私じゃないよ｡
夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday
私は夏休みが来てほしい｡
I want it to be summer break already!
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 友達[ともだち]:friend/companion, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun, 笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|
早く先輩と友達になって
楽しく笑いたい｡
I want to have fun and laugh with you as friends!
望む[のぞむ]:to desire|to wish for|to see
それしか望んでない！
That's all I want!
Stop lying to yourself.
ウソをつく:to tell a lie/to fib, やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
もう自分にｳｿをつくのはやめろ｡
正義[せいぎ]:justice/right/righteousness, 女子高生[じょしこうせい]:female high-school student
お前は正義の女子高生だろ｡
You're a high school girl in her prime.
なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
古賀にできないことなんてない｡
Nothing is impossible for you.
No fair. You can't say that.
ずるい:sly/cunning|miserly, 言い方[いいかた]:way of talking/speaking style
ずるい… ずるいよ そんな言い方｡
我慢[がまん]:patience/endurance/perseverance
だからさ
もう我慢しなくていいんだ｡
So you don't have to hold it in anymore.
You jerk! You colossal jerk!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 嫌い[きらい]:dislike|suspicion|distinction, 嫌い[ぎらい]:dislike/hatred/fear, 大嫌い[だいきらい]:detestable/abhorrent/loathsome
先輩のﾊﾞｶ ﾊﾞｶ！ 嫌い！ 大嫌い｡
I hate you! I hate you so much!
でも でも…｡
But... But...
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
好き…｡
I like you.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
私は先輩が好き…｡
I like you, Senpai.
大好き[だいすき]:loveable/very likeable/like very much
大好き～!!
I love you!
頑張る[がんばる]:to persevere|to insist that|to remain in a place
古賀 よく頑張ったな｡
Well done, Koga.
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 頑張る[がんばる]:to persevere|to insist that|to remain in a place
ﾎﾝﾄ頑張った｡
You fought really well.
The Japanese team have done it!
Japan Wins
日本[にほん, にっぽん]:Japan, 代表[だいひょう]:representative/representation/delegation
やってくれました 日本代表｡
テレビ:television/TV, おはようございます:good morning, 金曜日[きんようび]:Friday
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]おはようございます
今日は ６月27日 金曜日｡
Good morning. Today is Friday, June 27th.
Let's start with soccer.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
お… すげえな あいつ｡
Wow, she's something else.
It was all a simulation of the future?
Japan Wins
最初[さいしょ]:beginning/outset/first, 全部[ぜんぶ]:all/entire/whole, 未来[みらい]:the future (usually distant)|future tense|the world to come, シミュレーション:simulation
最初から 全部
未来のｼﾐｭﾚｰｼｮﾝだったのかよ｡
July 18th
June 27th
Uh, Mai-san.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
あの… 麻衣さん｡
何よ？
What?
I love you. Please go out with me.
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
好きです つきあってください｡
か月[かげつ]:months (period of), 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 感ずる[かんずる]:to feel/to sense
１か月間 同じこと言われてると
何も感じなくなる｡
After hearing that every day for a month,
I don't feel anything anymore.
My heart doesn't skip a beat.
ときめく:to throb/to flutter/to palpitate, ときめく:to be prosperous/to prosper/to flourish, 失恋[しつれん]:disappointed love/broken heart/unrequited love
ときめかない｡
そっか 失恋か｡
I see. I'm being rejected, huh?
新しい[あたらしい]:new/novel/fresh, 恋[こい]:(romantic) love, 探す[さがす]:to search (for something desired, needed)/to look for|to search (for something lost)
じゃあ
新しい恋を探すしかないな｡
I guess I'll have to find a new love.
今まで[いままで]:until now/so far/up to the present, ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks, ござる:to be
え？ ちょっ…｡
今まで ありがとうございました｡
Huh? Wai—
Thank you for everything.
H-Hey, I didn't say no.
諦める[あきらめる]:to give up/to abandon (hope, plans)/to resign oneself (to)
ﾀﾞﾒとは言ってない｡
なに諦めようとしてるのよ｡
Why are you just giving up?
Will you go out with me, then?
なら いいの？
生意気[なまいき]:impertinent/saucy/cheeky
咲太のくせに生意気…｡
You're too cheeky, Sakuta.
Is that a yes?
いいの？
Yes. Let's go out.
うん いいよ…｡
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
あのさ 麻衣さんって
僕のこと どう思ってる？
Say, Mai-san, how do you feel about me?
How I feel? That's...
どうって それは…｡
それは？
いいでしょ べつに｡
Go on.
Who cares?
I care. That's why I'm asking.
よくないから聞いてるんだけど｡
どうしても聞きたい？
はい｡
Do you really want to know?
Yes.
これでわかったでしょ？
Do you get it now?
マウス:mouse (esp. laboratory)
お… ﾏｳｽ ﾄｩ ﾏｳｽがよかったな｡
I would've preferred mouth-to-mouth.
Don't push your luck.
調子に乗る[ちょうしにのる]:to be elated/to be excited|to get up to speed
調子に乗るな｡
ｲﾃｯ｡
Ow.
なさる:to do
(朋絵)ごめんなさい｡
I'm sorry. I can't go out with you,
Maesawa-senpai.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, つきあえる:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあえる:to poke each other/to jab each other
私 前沢先輩とはつきあえません｡
You don't have a boyfriend, right?
彼氏[かれし]:boyfriend, とかい:city|Tokyo Metropolitan Assembly, とかい:crossing the sea
(前沢)今 彼氏とかいないよな？
はい｡
Right.
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
じゃあ 好きなやついるの？
Do you have someone you like, then?
Yeah. He's a dinosaur who doesn't even have a cell phone in this day and age.
いまどき:these days/nowadays|at this time (of the day), スマホ:smartphone/smart phone, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||, 原始[げんし]:origin/beginning|primeval
はい… その人は いまどき
ｽﾏﾎも持ってない原始人です｡
原始[げんし]:origin/beginning|primeval
誰が原始人だ？
あっ｡
Who're you calling a dinosaur?
Hey, I didn't mention you by name.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
べつに 先輩のことだなんて
言ってない｡
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 責任[せきにん]:duty/responsibility (incl. supervision of staff)|liability
それより先輩 責任とってよ｡
責任？
Anyway, you'd better take responsibility, Senpai.
Responsibility?
嫌う[きらう]:to hate/to dislike/to loathe, クラス:class, 居る[いる]:to be (of animate objects)|to stay|verb indicating continuing action or state (i.e. to be ..ing, to have been ..ing), 居る[おる]:to be (animate)|verb indicating continuing action or state (i.e. to be ..ing)|indicates contempt or disdain for another's actions, 場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho, なくなる:to die, なくなる:to be lost (e.g. luggage)/to be missing|to be used up
これで 玲奈ちゃんに嫌われて
ｸﾗｽに居場所なくなるんだから｡
Rena-chan's gonna hate me now, and I'll lose my place in class.
責任[せきにん]:duty/responsibility (incl. supervision of staff)|liability, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
なんで その責任が僕にくる？
だって 先輩のせいだし｡
How is that my responsibility?
I mean, it is your fault.
理由[りゆう, わけ]:reason/pretext/motive
理由を聞こうか｡
May I ask why?
You're the one who made me grow up.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 大人[おとな, だいにん]:adult, 大人[たいじん]:man of substance or virtue|giant|adult, じゃん:isn't it
先輩が私を大人にしたんじゃん｡
That sounded kinda lewd.
エロい:erotic/pornographic|eminent, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
なんかｴﾛいな｡
先輩って わかってるくせに
Why do you always deflect when
people talk to you from the heart?
照れ隠し[てれかくし]:hiding one's embarrassment
いつも そういうこと言うよね｡
照れ隠し？
Trying to hide the blush?
友達[ともだち]:friend/companion
まっ 古賀に何かあっても
友達でいてやるよ｡
Well, no matter what happens to you, I'll still be your friend.
ひとりぼっち:aloneness/loneliness/solitude
だから
ひとりぼっちにはならない｡
So don't worry.
You won't be left all alone.
Hey, I'm the one giving you the privilege of being best friends with me.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 親友[しんゆう]:close friend/bosom (old, intimate) friend/buddy, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
先輩を親友にしてあげるの
私のほうだし｡
夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday, 始まる[はじまる]:to begin|to happen (again)|to date (from), 期間[きかん]:period/term/interval
《それから
夏休みが始まるまでの期間は
Each day from then till the start of summer break
was filled with unsurprising surprises.
驚き[おどろき, オドロキ]:surprise/astonishment/wonder, 連続[れんぞく]:serial/consecutive/continuity
驚きの連続だった｡
体験[たいけん]:personal experience/physical experience/one's own experience, 日々[ひび, にちにち]:every day/daily/day after day, 実際[じっさい]:practicality|reality|bhutakoti (limit of reality), とおり:avenue/street|coming and going, とおり:penetration (as of light)
僕と古賀が体験した日々は
実際に そのとおりになった｡
The days Koga and I lived out came to pass in reality.
先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.), 新人[しんじん]:new face/newcomer|modern humans (from Cro-Magnon man onwards)
ﾊﾞｲﾄ先に 古賀が新人として
入ってきて
Koga joined my workplace as a new hire.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.), 仕事[しごと]:work/job|work, 服[ふく]:clothes (esp. Western clothes)|counter for doses of medicine, gulps of tea, drags of a cigarette, etc., 服[ぶく]:mourning clothes|mourning/period of mourning
麻衣さんは かえでに
仕事で使った服をくれ
Mai-san gave Kaede an outfit she modeled for work,
仕事[しごと]:work/job|work
そのあと仕事で 鹿児島に行き
went to Kagoshima for a shoot,
and tutored me as a bunny girl once she got back.
帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home, バニーガール:bunny girl, 格好[かっこう, かっこ]:shape|appearance|state||, 勉強[べんきょう]:study|diligence|discount, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach
帰ってからは ﾊﾞﾆｰｶﾞｰﾙの格好で
僕に勉強を教えてくれた｡
期末[きまつ]:end of term, 試験[しけん]:examination/exam|trial, 内容[ないよう]:subject/contents/matter, そっくり:all/altogether|exactly like, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway
期末試験の内容まで
そっくり同じだ》
Even the questions on the finals were the exact same.
なるほど:I see/That's right!/Indeed, 周囲[しゅうい]:surroundings/environs|circumference, 合わせる[あわせる]:to match (rhythm, speed, etc.)|to join together|to face||
なるほどね 周囲に合わせるため
I see.
The girl who was desperately trying to fit in
by keeping an eye out for social cues
必死[ひっし]:frantic|inevitable death|brinkmate (inevitable checkmate), 空気を読む[くうきをよむ]:to read the situation/to sense the mood, 少女[しょうじょ, おとめ]:little girl/maiden|female between 17 and 20 years old (ritsuryo period)
必死で空気を読んでいた少女は
became capable of seeing
the future at some point, huh?
気がつく[きがつく]:to notice|to be scrupulous|to recover consciousness, 未来[みらい]:the future (usually distant)|future tense|the world to come
気がつくと 未来まで
読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess
読めるように
なっていたわけだ｡
But out of over seven billion people,
why was I the only one dragged into it?
億[おく]:10^8/100,000,000/hundred million, 人類[じんるい]:mankind/humanity
でも どうして
70億の人類の中で
現象[げんしょう]:phenomenon, 巻き込む[まきこむ]:to roll up/to enfold|to involve
僕だけが その現象に
巻き込まれたんだろう？
量子もつれ[りょうしもつれ]:quantum entanglement, 量子[りょうし]:quantum, つれる:to lead/to take (a person), つれる:to have a cramp|to be pulled too tight
量子もつれじゃないの？
量子もつれ？ なんだ それ？
Quantum entanglement, no?
Quantum entanglement? What's that?
Sometimes, pairs of distant particles, without any connection at all,
離れる[はなれる]:to be separated|to leave|to leave (a job, etc.)|, 位置[いち]:place/situation/position, 粒子[りゅうし]:particle/grain, 媒介[ばいかい]:intermediary, 必要とする[ひつようとする]:to need/to call for/to require
離れた位置にある２つの粒子が
何の媒介も必要とせずに
瞬時[しゅんじ]:moment/instant, 情報[じょうほう]:information/news|information, 共有[きょうゆう]:joint ownership/co-ownership/sharing, 動く[うごく]:to move|to operate|to be touched||, 奇妙[きみょう]:strange/queer/curious, 現象[げんしょう]:phenomenon
瞬時に情報を共有して動く
奇妙な現象のこと｡
can instantly share information and
act together in a strange phenomenon.
You mean to say Koga and I
got entangled and synced up?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
つまり 双葉は 僕と古賀が
もつれる:to get entangled/to get tangled|to have poor control over (one's tongue, feet, etc.), 同期[どうき]:same period|same year (of graduation, entering a company, etc.)|synchronization, たって:strongly hoping or requesting (of something that is difficult to be brought to fruition), たって:even if/even though|however
もつれて同期したって
言いたいのか？
もつれる:to get entangled/to get tangled|to have poor control over (one's tongue, feet, etc.)
そっ｡
けど なんで もつれるんだよ｡
Yep.
But why'd we get entangled in the first place?
量子[りょうし]:quantum, もつれ:tangle/entanglement|complication, 起こる[おこる]:to occur/to happen, 粒子[りゅうし]:particle/grain, 同士[どうし, どし]:fellow/mutual/companion, 衝突[しょうとつ]:collision/crash|conflict
量子もつれが起こるのは
粒子同士が衝突したあと｡
Quantum entanglement happens after the particles collide.
年生[ねんせい]:pupil in ... year/student in ... year, 最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, 衝撃[しょうげき]:shock/impact/crash, 与える[あたえる]:to give (esp. to someone of lower status)|to provide|to assign||, 合う[あう, おう]:to come together|to fit|to be profitable|
その１年生と 最近 何か
衝撃を与え合ったりしなかった？
Did you clash with that first-year in any way recently?
尻[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|, 尻[しり]:buttocks|undersurface|last place|, 蹴る[ける]:to kick|to refuse/to reject, 合う[あう, おう]:to come together|to fit|to be profitable|
あっ… 尻を蹴り合った｡
Oh...
We kicked each other's butts.
梓川｡
あ？
Azusagawa.
再現[さいげん]:reappearance/reproduction/return, 実験[じっけん]:experiment, 尻[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|, 尻[しり]:buttocks|undersurface|last place|
再現実験をしたい 尻を出せ｡
I want to verify its reproducibility.
Turn around and bend over.
断る[ことわる]:to refuse|to inform|to ask leave
断る｡
いいから出せ ﾌﾞﾀ野郎｡
I refuse.
Do it now, you pig.
I can't wait to see you
in an apron, Mai-san.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, エプロン:apron, 姿[すがた]:figure|appearance|state||, 楽しみ[たのしみ]:enjoyment/pleasure|anticipation
麻衣さんのｴﾌﾟﾛﾝ姿
楽しみだな｡
料理[りょうり]:cooking/cookery|dealing with something, エプロン:apron
私 料理のときは
ｴﾌﾟﾛﾝしないけど｡
I don't wear one
when I cook, though.
え～｡
はいはい わかったわよ｡
What?
Okay, fine. I'll wear one.
How about just the apron?
裸[はだか]:naked/nude/bare, エプロン:apron, 下剤[げざい]:laxative, 入れる[いれる]:to put in|to admit|to accept||, かしら:I wonder, かしら:head|hair (on one's head)
なんなら 裸ｴﾌﾟﾛﾝでも｡
下剤でも入れようかしら｡
Maybe I should mix a laxative into the food.
冗談[じょうだん, ぎだん]:jest/joke/funny story, 本気[ほんき]:seriousness/earnestness/truth
冗談です｡
本気だったくせに｡
I was kidding.
Please. I know you were serious.
どうしたの？
あっ この子が…｡
What's wrong?
This cat.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 傘[かさ]:umbrella/parasol|something shaped like an umbrella or a conical hat, 傘[からかさ]:paper umbrella/bamboo-and-paper umbrella parasol
麻衣さん 傘いい？
うん｡
Mind holding the umbrella, Mai-san?
Sure.
I'll take it to my place for now.
とりあえず:first of all/at once|for now, 連れていく[つれていく, つれてゆく]:to take someone (to some place)/to take someone along/to lead someone away
とりあえず うちに連れていくよ｡
あっ でも その子
But I'd like to keep it.
引き取る[ひきとる]:to take over|to take charge of|to retire to a private place, 連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|
私 引き取りたいんです｡
だったら あとで連絡して｡
Call me later, then.
I'll give you my landline number.
電話番号[でんわばんごう]:telephone number, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach
うちの電話番号 教えるから｡
僕は 梓川咲太｡
I'm Azusagawa Sakuta.
サービスエリア:service area (usu. an area off a highway to buy gasoline, etc. for vehicles), 花[はな]:flower|cherry blossom|beauty||, 咲く[さく]:to bloom
梓川ｻｰﾋﾞｽｴﾘｱの梓川に
花咲く太郎の咲太｡
Azusagawa from "Azusagawa Service Area,"
and Sakuta from "Hanasaku Tarou."
私は…｡
My name...
is Makinohara Shouko.
牧之原翔子といいます｡
That's my Azusagawa. A total pig.
Next Episode
#7: Youth Is a Paradox